Bathandwa Samfumfana

East London, South Africa, 5201

Email: bathie28@gmail.com Mobile: +27 724874779

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bathandwas

Professional Summary

Offering over 10 years of extensive experience in the automotive industry with a specialized background in **Mechatronics, Electrical & Robotics**. Having completed a **Diploma in Network Systems** in 2022, I am currently pursuing an **Advanced Diploma in Industrial Data Communication, Network, and IT** in order to align with the emerging lot & AI technologies in Industries. My technical acumen and commitment to continuous professional development make me a valuable asset to forward-thinking organizations in the industry.

Experience

Tesla Gigafactory

Maintenance Technician (Model Y - B.I.W),

November 2023 - April 2024 EU-DE-Berlin-

Tesla Straße (Germany) · On-site

- Troubleshoot and rectify faults on complex manufacturing machines, servo systems, AC variable frequency drives.
- Performed comprehensive maintenance, refurbishment, and modifications, contributing to preventive maintenance initiatives on mechanical systems (conveyors), pneumatics and hydraulics.
- Document all technical procedures, including maintenance breakdowns and troubleshooting reports.
- Adhered to strict safety guidelines **(electrical/mechanical)** and accident prevention regulations.
- Work extensively with interfaced controls for process optimization, visualization systems (HMI and SCADA)
- Experience with Kuka, Fanuc robotics and a intermediate understanding of PLC systems

Mercedes-Benz South Africa,

Maintenance Mechatronic Technician

January 2010 - November 2016

East London, Eastern Cape, South Africa

- Troubleshoot and rectify faults on complex manufacturing machines, servo drives systems (Siemens Lenze)

- Performed comprehensive maintenance, refurbishment, and modifications, contributing to preventive maintenance initiatives on mechanical and electrical systems **(Conveyors)**, pneumatics and hydraulics **(Festo)**
- Managed robotic operations, including teaching and programming robot paths (**Kuka**), tool center point systems.
- Developed and maintained human machine interface devices **(HMI, SCADA)** and associated softwares like **(SAP System)** ensuring seamless operation in daily production targets.

Mercedes-Benz South Africa, Robotics Support (Assembly-shop)

January 2017 - November 2023 East London, Eastern Cape, South Africa

- Trainer & Support for Assembly gluing/Sealer technology (**Roof & Windshield**) glue application.
- Employed vision systems (**Quiss camera**) in robotic applications for accurate path correction and guidance, crucial in assembly and body shop operations.
- Carry out Total Preventative Maintenance **(TPM)** and continuous improvements in the production shop-floor environment.
- Use and implementation of IT production systems and IT/Industrial Network troubleshooting.

Education

Engineering Institute of Technology

Advanced Diploma of Industrial Data Communication, Network and IT, 2023 - November 2024 (In progress)

West Perth WA 6005, (Australia) · Remote

Boston City Campus

Diploma **(DIP.)** Network Systems, 2020 - December 2022 East London, Eastern Cape, South Africa

Mercedes Benz Technical Training Centre

Mechatronics Engineering (Apprenticeship)

2004 - December 2009